software engineering radio episode 35
roadmap and programming over the winter
[Music]
welcome everybody this out-of-band
episode of software engineering radio in
this episode I mainly want to tell you
about the great new stuff we have coming
up over the next couple of months but
before we do that I'd like to ask you to
help us not by giving us money but
rather by helping us make se radio more
widely known the feedback we get from
you through email through comments on
our website or or at the comments page
at podcast la is really great so this
tells us that people who know software
engineering radio will most likely like
it the problem is that we think that
still not enough people have heard about
as your radio so we'd like you to help
us there so I'd like to make a couple of
suggestions how you could help us to
make us more widely known one way is to
add more votes and comments at podcast
la currently we have 38 votes we have
many many thousands of listeners so you
know if maybe every other listener would
give us a vote then we'd have a couple
of thousand votes and that would be
really something
38 is not so impressive compared with
some of the other podcasts another way
how you could help us is of course by
telling your friends I think you do that
already so just continue doing that
however you could also you know scale
this telling your friends up a little
bit for example if you know the editors
of some kind of news or Java or
technology related website you might be
able to put us in contact with these
people
so we could discuss with them whether
they would like to point their audiences
to su radio after all we're not a
competition to any you know typical
website or news service another way you
can help us is by
writing you know a little little piece
of text a little little article for
computer magazines especially
non-english speaking magazines for
example if you live in Greece you might
want to write a couple of lines of
information about as you radio in some
Greek developer magazine obviously we
can't do it ourselves because we don't
speak Greek
so we have kind of you know take a look
at the German news magazine market and
we have arranged a couple of things
there but we can't do much outside of
Germany because we don't know the people
who are well so you could help us there
also so if you want to do us a favor you
know help us in one of the ways I just
outlined or do something else to make se
radio more more widely known and that'll
be really great so thanks for that okay
so let's get to the main reason for this
episode I wanted to tell you about some
of the upcoming episodes at the Giroux
conference and our who's in Denmark as
well as at Uppsala 2006 in Portland
Oregon in the u.s. I've recorded a
couple of very interesting interviews
and also we've been producing a number
of very cool episodes within the team
and I'm going to tell you which these
are so you know what you should do about
the winter time you know if you can't go
out and do reasonable things outside you
probably have to listen to podcasts so
we're going to provide you with a lot of
good stuff you can listen to so the next
episode we were going to have is
actually going to be one of our
highlights we've got an interview with
guys deal guys deal is a research fellow
at Sun he's a really big name in the
language design community he has you
know been very involved with Liz Benton
is in this discussion in this episode
he'll talk about for us a new
programming language that should replace
Fortran a very interesting episode will
then also have two episodes on extreme
programming coming up these are team
internal episodes by Anna and Alexander
another person
going to have as an interview partner
Stefano ski he is one of the really
well-known names in the middleware
community he has implemented I don't
know six or seven core bar orbs so he's
a real real authority there will then
have another episode in architecture or
part four before we are going to look at
very large scale architecture because
we're actually going to talk to the CTO
of Amazon one of Fogle's he was kind
enough to give us an interview at you
talking about scalability and other
issues you know if you build systems at
the scale of Amazon we then have an
episode about a design by a contract you
know the stuff that has been implemented
in Eiffel we then have something about
safety critical systems technical issues
as well as some discussion about the
development process and will come up
with our first episode and product line
engineering later then we'll have an
interview with Lauren strat he is
working for I think King's College in
London I hope I didn't screw that up I
always miss the mix this up with
University College and I never know
where he is and if I if I mentioned the
wrong one he's probably angry with me
but okay so I think it's Kings College
and he's going to talk about
implementing domain-specific languages
using compiler metaprogramming another
one of these language conceptual
episodes I think those are really great
then we have an interview with Gregor
hope he will talk about messaging and
the price application integration
process orchestration and these kinds of
things another really interesting topic
is architectural analysis and evaluation
with Drago's marinesko
another interview we recorded at the
cello conference we also have an
interview with Obi Fernandez about
implementing DSL in Ruby so another
dynamic language is thing coming up but
that's not all we have more we have an
interview with Brian gets and david
holmes the authors of this new
concurrency in practice book Java
concurrency in practice actually about
advanced
topics in concurrency it's not going to
be Java specific we have interview with
Jonathan Aldrich and he's going to talk
about static analysis tools Martin
deters will talk about compiler
construction and the internals of the
GNU C compiler GCC will have a
roundtable discussion about product line
engineering and model driven development
recorded at the product line and model
oven development conference in Leipzig
in October 2006 we have a discussion
with Stephan Stephan share for he will
talk about central sensor networks
wireless software mobile software and
these kinds of things and finally we
have round table discussion about ultra
large scale systems with Linda Northrup
dark Schmidt Gregor kisailus and Kevin
Sullivan so these are the things we've
already recorded we are currently in the
at approach in the process of recording
more stuff for example we'll have two
episodes and refactoring we'll have
stuff on aspect orientation and so on
and so on we also signed up a couple of
very very interesting people for
additional interviews but I will stay
with my policy of not announcing the
names of these interviewees until we
have recorded the interview for the
obvious reasons because it's always
actually hard to schedule these things
it's not that people don't want to give
us interviews it's more like you know
getting together and finding a time slot
where everybody has time and by the way
the order of the announcements in this
episode is not significant so I might I
might change the order and I also might
inject additional stuff in-between or
rearrange things but this is the stuff
we have you know on the hard disk it
will be broadcasted at some point during
the winter I hope this gave you a
reasonable impression of what the winner
on a radio will look like please give us
feedback let us know what you liked
which topics you would like to hear and
as I mentioned beginning of the
beginning of the podcast please help us
advertise as your radio we have so much
cool stuff
I think it's cool if more people can
listen to it and will know about SU
radio ok that's all for today short
episode thanks for listening and hear
you in a couple
stays with the interview what guys feel
fine
[Music]
thanks for listening to software
engineering radio if you want to get
more information about software
engineering radio or if you want to give
us feedback please go to our website at
se - radio dot net you can also contact
the team at team at se
- radio net although we prefer entries
in our comment system on the website so
other people can see what you think
software engineering radio wants to
thank Henning Poli for the intro and
outro music as well as Lipson for
providing the bandwidth this episode of
se radio as well as all other episodes
is licensed under Creative Commons
license see the software engineering
radio website for details